Let the game begin...
Escape Room is a horror, thriller, fantasy film directed by Peter Dukes.
Four friends who partake in a popular Los Angeles escape room find
themselves stuck with a demonically possessed killer.
They have less than an hour to solve the puzzles
needed to escape the room alive.
Brice, played by Skeet Ulrich.
Ramona, played by Sean Young.
Jess, played by Christine Donlon.
Jeff, played by Randy Wayne.
Ben, played by Matt McVay.
Angie, played by Ashley Gallegos.
Escape Room is a 2019 American psychological horror survival film
directed by Adam Robitel from a screenplay by Bragi F.
Schut and Maria Melnik, based on a story conceived by Schut.
The film stars Taylor Russell, Logan Miller, Deborah Ann Woll, Tyler Labine, Nik Dodani, Jay Ellis, and Yorick van
Wageningen, and follows a group of people who are sent to navigate a series of deadly escape rooms.
Development of the film began in August 2017, then under the
title The Maze, and the casting process commenced.
Schut and Melnik were hired to write the screenplay, and
Robitel was confirmed to be directing.
Filming took place in South Africa in late 2017 through January 2018.
Brian Tyler and Jon Carey were hired to compose the
film's score, with Tyler also conducting.
Escape Room was released in the United States on January 4, 2019,
by Columbia Pictures (via Sony Pictures Releasing).
It grossed over $155 million worldwide and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its atmosphere, cast, and
production design, but criticized the familiar plot and its failure to take full advantage of its premise.
It was followed by the sequel Escape Room: Tournament of Champions in 2021.
The tone is dark and intense.